

# **ALEXANDER** VANDENBROUCKE

# PHD RESEARCHER IN PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

London

Tel: +447384312813

Email: alexander.vandenbroucke@gmail.com

Website:

https://https://alexandervandenbroucke.github.io/ GitHub:

https://github.com/alexandervandenbroucke

Bitbucket:

https://bitbucket.org/AlexanderV/



# PROFILE SUMMARY

I caught the FP bug during my Master's Thesis, working on applying logic-programming techniques in a functional setting. I worked in the intersection of FP, LP and probabilistic programming, with a particular interest in semantics during my PhD. Currently a Quantitative developer (a "strat") at Standard Chartered Bank.



# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Fixing Non-Determinism. Alexander Vandenbroucke, Tom Schriivers and Frank Piessens. In IFL'15, 2016.
- Tabling with Sound Answer Subsumption. Alexander Vandenbroucke, Maciej Piróg, Benoit Desouter and Tom Schrijvers. In TPLP special issue for ICLP 2016, 2016.
- PloNK: Functional Probabilistic NetKAT. Alexander Vandenbroucke and Tom Schrijvers. In PACMPL 4. POPL 2020, 2020.
- Disjunctive Delimited Control. Alexander Vandenbroucke and Tom Schrijvers. LOPSTR 2021. 2021. (Best Paper Award)
- Forward- or Reverse-Mode Automatic Differentiation: What's the Difference? Birthe Van den Bergh, Tom Schrijvers, James McKinna and Alexander Vandenbroucke. Science of Computer Programming, Volume 231, 2024.
- Rigged Contracts. Alexander Vandenbroucke and Tom Schrijvers. FLOPS 2024. 2024



# OTHER SKILLS

- Academic writing and public speaking
- Co-organised IFL2016 Symposium
- Fighting on the fencing piste since 2001



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### QUANTITATIVE DEVELOPER

# Standard Chartered | April 2021 - Present

I am part of a team that develops and maintains a back-end Haskell service delivering pricing quotes to traders. We own the entire software development process, from requirements to development, deployment, support and infrastructure.

#### PHD STUDENT

#### KU Leuven | August 2015 - December 2020

Until 2017, I worked on internal funding to apply advanced functional programming techniques to logic programming. In January 2017, I obtained external project funding from the FWO investigate harnessing probabilistic programming for network problems (4 year project).



# **EDUCATION**

# **KU LEUVEN**

### PhD: Engineering Science: Computer Science

- Grades are not conferred for Doctoral Degrees at KU Leuven
- Attended from 2015 to 2020

#### **MSc: Engineering Science: Computer Science**

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Attended from 2013 to 2015

# UNIVERSITY OF ANTWERP

# BSc: Informatics

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Attended from 2010 to 2013



# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

### Languages I'm really good at

Haskell

# Languages I know

- C/C++
- Java
- Python
- Prolog
- HTML/Javascript
- Dhall

#### Other

• Kubernetes / EKS